What are we talking about when we talk about outliers?
离群值是什么意思？
We're talking about extreme or unexpected values in
离群值是指市场数据中的极端或意外值
market data which may or may not represent real events.
它们可能并不代表真实情况
For example, if we're tracking a solar energy company stock price,
例如 如果我们观察太阳能公司的股价
we might see unexpected movements in the price on a day when a solar eclipse occurs.
可能会发现在发生日食的那一天股价出现意外的变化
Outliers can show up for
离群值可能是由无数种原因导致的
a million different reasons but some reasons are more common than others.
但通常都是某几类原因造成的
In this video, we're going to talk about a few of the most common types of outliers.
在本视频中 我们将讨论几种最常见的离群值
Outliers can always appear due to human error,
离群值经常是由人为错误导致的
either during manual data entry or in the form of computer bugs.
可能会在手动输入过程中出现或是某些程序错误
These are known as fat finger errors.
称之为胖手指失误
To cite a few examples that had newsworthy consequences,
举几个造成轰动性后果的例子
in 2001 a Japanese traitor cost his employer UBS Warburg,
在 2001 年 一名日本交易员本应以 610,000 日元出售 6 股股票
71 million pounds when he sold 610,000 shares at
他却以 6 日元售出 610,000 股股票
60 yen instead of six shares at 610,000 yen as he had intended.
导致他的公司瑞银华宝损失 7100 万英镑
In 2015, a junior member of
在 2015 年 德意志银行
Deutsche Bank's foreign exchange sales team processed a trade using
外汇销售团队的一名资历较浅的员工
a gross figure rather than a net figure causing
在处理一笔交易时使用的是总值 而不是净值
a payment to a U.S. hedge fund of six billion dollars,
导致向一家美国对冲基金支付了 60 亿美元
orders of magnitude too high.
达到很高的数量级
Sometimes data can be missing completely,
有时候 数据会完全丢失
entered as zeros or duplicated from previous states.
出现为零 或与之前的数字重复
This can happen due to lax quality control of market data vendors but sometimes exchanges
发生这种情况的原因可能是市场数据供应商缺少质量控制措施
themselves can be missing data.
但有时候交易本身也会缺少数据
Data maybe missing because the stock was suspended from
股票可能会在某一天暂停交易
trading for a day or more often, for part of a day.
更多时候是一天的某个时段暂停交易 导致缺少数据
Trading on a stock can be stopped for regulatory reasons,
股票可能会因为监管原因而暂停交易
to reduce volatile trading prior to a companies news announcement
目的是在公司宣布重大事项之前减少波动性交易
or when there's uncertainty about whether the stock continues to meet listing standards.
或者是因为不确定股票是否继续满足上市标准
It can also be stopped for non-regulatory reasons.
也有可能因为非监管原因而暂停
For example, if there's a significant imbalance and pending buy and sell orders.
例如 待处理的买卖委托之间非常不平衡
In these cases, one way to check if trading actually
在这些情形下 检查交易是否实际发生的一种方式是
occurred is to check if the trade volume was zero.
检查成交量是否为零
Trading for an entire exchange can also be stopped.
整个证交所也可能会暂停交易
There are mechanisms called trading curves or circuit
如果某个指数下跌一定的百分比
breakers that halt trading if an index drops by a certain percent.
就会采用熔断机制暂停交易
The idea is to prevent stock market crashes,
目的是防止股市崩盘
events when the prices of stocks across
崩盘是指大量股价
a significant cross section of the market drops suddenly and significantly.
忽然大幅下跌
You might also see extreme price movements that are due to real events such as earnings,
有些真实事件也可能会导致出现极端价格
mergers or other announcements.
例如收益 企业合并或其他企业通告
Announcements represent information that the market previously did not know.
通告表示市场之前不知道的信息
So these can surprise the general market if the results are much
如果通告结果比市场预期的好很多或坏很多
better or worse than the market expected, so to speak.
就会使普通市场人士很吃惊
When the market adjusts to this information,
当市场适应这些信息时
the stock price fluctuates as
股价会波动
the new information starts to be reflected in the trading price.
交易价格将开始体现这些新的信息
For example, the athletic apparel company, Puma,
例如 运动服装公司彪马
made an unexpected earnings announcement on October 18th,
在 2017 年 10 月 18 日发出意外收益通告
2017 in which it reported stronger than expected third-quarter earnings.
报告列出了比第三季度预期更高的收益
That day, its stock closed four percent higher than
当天 彪马收盘价
the previous day's close and the subsequent days
比前一天的收盘价高出 4%
saw fluctuations as the price rose still further.
后续几天价格出现波动并持续上升
Outliers can occur due to
计算机交易程序的
the intended or unintended actions of computer trading programs.
预期或意外操作可能会导致离群值
For example, in 2010 the market experienced
例如 在 2010 年
a flash crash which lasted only 36 minutes and was later linked to trading algorithms.
市场出现闪电崩盘 仅持续了 36 分钟 之后发现闪崩与一个交易算法有关
While extreme price fluctuations occurred during this short period,
虽然在这个简短时间内出现极端价格波动
they were due to real events.
但是它们是由真实事件造成的
Sometimes quants must work with
有时候 量化分析师
unadjusted or nominal price data
需要处理未经调整的价格或名义价格数据
because adjusted price data are unavailable through their data source,
因为数据源无法提供经过调整的价格数据
when working with real time data directly from a stock exchange for example.
例如直接处理证交所的实时数据
If you are working with unadjusted price data,
在处理未经调整的股价数据时
you will see discontinuities in prices on dates when companies issue dividends,
你会发现 当企业派发股息 拆分股票
split their stock or took other corporate actions.
或采取其他企业行为时 股价会出现波动
Companies may issue dividends on a regular schedule
企业可能会定期派发股息
or may decide to issue one-off so-called special dividends.
也可能会派发一次性股息 称为特别股利
In this example, you can see that in 2017,
在此图中可以看到
Costco issued several regular dividends as
在 2017 年 Costco 多次定期派发了股息
well as a large seven dollar per share special dividend.
并且一次性派发了数额很高的 7 美元/股特别股利
These discontinuities can look like outliers if returns are calculated on these data.
如果根据这些数据计算收益 这些波动看起来就像离群值
A stock trades ex-dividend on or after the ex-dividend date,
股票会在除息日当日或之后按除息价交易
so on this date, non-adjusted prices decrease.
所以在此日期 未经调整的价格会下降
This represents the fact that the net company value has
这表明公司净值降低了
decreased because cash has been transferred from the company to shareholders.
因为现金从公司转移到了股东身上
However, after prices are adjusted,
但是 调整股价后
change demand for company stock may also cause prices to change.
对公司股票的需求变化也会导致股价变化
Price changes due to change demand are real market effects.
需求变化导致的股价变化是真实的市场影响
To deal with discontinuities in unadjusted prices,
为了处理未调整价格的不连续问题
whoever is cleaning the data must go back,
清理数据的人必须检查历史数据
look at corporate events and cumulatively adjust
查看企业事件并根据每次股息派发事件逐个调整价格
for each dividend distribution to generate adjusted prices.
从而生成调整后股价